Guide to the Betty Bone Schiess papers, 1965-2014
Schiess, Betty Bone papers, 1965-2014
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Betty Bone Schiess papers, 1965-2014
4468
Betty Bone. Schiess
15.2 cubic ft., 1 map case folder
Correspondence, chronological and subject files, clippings, schedules, photographs, audio and video cassettes, biographical information, and legal documents.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, litigation files, documents, clippings, photographs, audio and video cassettes concerning the various causes and organizations with which Reverend Schiess was concerned, particularly the ordination of women and feminist issues.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Episcopal priest.
Betty Bone Schiess graduated from the University of Cincinnati in 1945. She received an M.A. from Syracuse University in 1947 and a Master of Divinity in 1972 from the Rochester Center for Theological Studies. In 1972, she was ordained a deacon of the Episcopal Church in the United States, and ordained as a priest in 1974. The ordination in 1974 in Philadelphia of eleven women by four inactive priests was deemed "irregular" in that it was done without approval of the General Convention of the Episcopal Church. Subsequently, Schiess and her attorney Constance Cook began a law suit against the Bishop of the Diocese of Central New York, Ned Cole, charging him with sex discrimination for refusing to recognize her ordination and preventing her from assuming the position of a parish priest. The suit was discontinued when the General Convention in 1975 approved the ordination of women to the priesthood in the Episcopal Church.
Reverend Schiess served as curate at Grace Episcopal Church in Baldwinsville, N.Y. in 1972-1973. From 1973 to 1984, she was Executive Director, Mizpah Educational and Cultural Center for the Aging in Syracuse; Priest Associate, Grace Episcopal Church, Syracuse; Chaplain, Syracuse University; and Acting Chaplain, Cornell University. She was installed as rector of Grace Church, Mexico, N.Y., in 1984 and became Advisor to Women in Mission and Ministry, Episcopal Church in the United States in 1987.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, litigation files, documents, clippings, photographs, audio and video cassettes concerning the various causes and organizations with which Reverend Schiess was concerned, particularly the ordination of women and feminist issues. Organizations include the International Association of Women Ministers, the Episcopal Society for the Examination of Feminist Issues, the National Organization for Women, and the Movement for the Ordination of Women. Much of the material pertains to the July 1974 ordination of the "Philadelphia 11" and to the Lambeth Conference (England) and the General Convention of the Episcopal Church.
Files, 1889-1991, compiled by Lois M. Black relating to the Episcopal Society of the Examination of Feminist Issues and other topics relating to women's ordination. Includes a nomination submission for the National Women's Hall of Fame, 1994.
Book: Why Me Lord?; typescript paper "Goodbye to All That" explaining her current feelings about the Episcopal Church and women's issues; and cassette tape - New Zealand Public Radio, 1993. Annotated listing of the people who helped her. Copy of "The Little Yankee, From Riches to Rags: Letters of Mary Ann Corlis, 1815-1850," published letters of Betty Bone Schiess's ancestor, Mary Ann Corlis. Typescript notes about people who influenced her, titled "secularism, although still restrained by religious authorities."
Items relating to the 2014 Dewey-Heyward Lectures and EDS Women's Leadership Forum at the Episcopal Divinity School; and program for the 146th Convention of the Episcopal Diocese of Central New York, 2014.Also includes DVD and program for a celebration of Karen DeCrow by the Central New York Women's Bar Association, April 2015
SUBJECTS
Names:
Schiess, Betty Bone.; Cole, Ned.; Cornell University--Religion.; Episcopal Church.General Convention.; Episcopal Church. Diocese of Central New York.; Episcopal Church. Women in Mission and Ministry.; Grace Church (Mexico, N.Y.); Grace Episcopal Church (Baldwinsville, N.Y.); Grace Episcopal Church (Syracuse, N.Y.); International Association of Women Ministers.; Lambeth Conference.; Mizpah Educational and Cultural Center for the Aging (Syracuse, N.Y.); National Organization for Women.; Syracuse University--Religion.
Subjects:
Women clergy.; Ordination of women.; Women priests.; Religious institutions--New York (State)--Syracuse.; Religious institutions--New York (State)--Baldwinsville.; Religious institutions--New York (State)--Mexico.; Feminism--Religious aspects--Christianity.; Syracuse (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence and Other Files
Boxes 1-3, 6-9, 11, 12, 14-18
Series II. Audio Cassettes
Box 10, 15
Series III. Magnetic Stripe Film
Box 10
Series IV. Video Cassettes/DVD's
Box 10, 18
Series V. Tape Recordings
Box 10
Series VI. Film
Box 10
Series VII. Photographs
Box 11
Series VIII. Connie Cook Litigation Files
Box 4, 5, 13
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence and Other Files
  - Ordination of Women, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
  - General, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Betty Bone Schiess certificate of ordination, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Connie Cook, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - International Association of Women Ministers (IAWM), 1980-87 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - EcoTheater, 1980-89 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
  - Lois Black, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - General, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mary Alice [Burke] and Fanny [Heckin], 1982-89 (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
  - The Episcopal Society for the Examination of Feminist Issues (ESEFI), 1982-91 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - North Carolina: female circumcision, 1982-89 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - IAWM, 1974-87 (Box 1, Folder 24-26)
  - General, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
  - De Crow [Karen], 1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (addresses) January, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Family", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - IAWM, 1986-87 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Mary Alice Burke, 1986-88 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Katrina Swanson, 1986-88 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - General, 1986-88 (Box 1, Folder 36-37)
  - Roxy Burnett/Corrigans, 1986-89 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Mexico [NY] for Biographical material, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Biographical Material, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Walmsley [The Rt. Rev. Arthur E.], 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Biographical Material, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Grace Church, Mexico: biographical material, news, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cuomo - New York State Volunteers, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - North Carolina Women, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - North Carolina, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General, 1987-88 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
  - Mary Eunice Oliver, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Episcopal Church Women (ECW); Church Women United (CWU), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Carol George, 1988-89 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Aurelia Dixon McIntyre Klayf, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Nairobi - Past E/W - newspaper clippings, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bishop Whitaker, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Scott Evans, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Biographical Material: Sally Cone re. Lambeth; Mary Eunice re. Lambeth; Sally Cone: "Pine Needles", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Biographical Material re. Lambeth, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Lambeth, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Lambeth - proposals from women's groups New York comments, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Lambeth - gifts, ECW, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - "meat pie" - Golphin, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - News re. Lambeth, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Lambeth news articles, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Invention - Creativity [North Carolina Conference], 1988 (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
  - General Convention - Detroit, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - IAWM, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Biographical material, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 32-34)
  - University of California, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Brooklyn Unitarian Society, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - General, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Sally Cone, 1988-89 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - United Kingdom, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 40-42)
  - United Kingdom - newspaper clippings, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Jane G. Fry, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - General, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Barbara Harris, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Barbara Harris newspaper clippings, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Continuing Medical Education - SUNY Heath Center at Syracuse, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - National Organization for Women (NOW) news, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - General, 1965-66 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bishop Cole, 1968-73 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General, 1969-86 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - General, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
  - Women/General, 1970's (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - Hiatt-Meyn, 1970-72 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
  - General, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 14-17)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - General, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 19-21)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Leading up to 1974 ordination, 1973-74 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - General, 1973-76 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - The Event, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Letters re: Ordination, etc., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - The 1974 Ordination (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Chicago, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Aftermath of August meeting of Bishops, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 29-30)
  - Special General Convention re. Women, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - ESEFI, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
  - Theologians reactions, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - House of Bishops, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Commission on Ministry - Diocesan Council, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Bishop Cole, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Suspension, etc., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Other correspondence - opposition, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - General, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 40-42)
  - Grace Church employment, 1974-75 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Katrina et al, 1974-75 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Annotated listing of people who helped Betty, including "Secularism, although still restrained by religious authorities" (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - The Little Yankee, From Riches to Rags: Letters of Mary Ann Corlis, 1815-1850 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - NB Overview yes/no, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Allin/Jones Caper - Canadian Church, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Connie Cook/ Stringfellow, 1975-76 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - January-February, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - March-May, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - June-July, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - August-November, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bishop Cole, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Women's Ordination NOW (WON), 1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Church trials/Wendt, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Documents in support: Willie, Page, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Second Committee on Inquiry, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 2nd ordination, September 7, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Other "trials", 1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Federal trials, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Bishop of Main - Caper, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - General, correspondence, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 17-23)
  - New York State Council of Churches - Return of Death Law, 1975-76 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Other events, 1975-76 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Colgate meeting, 1975-76 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Celebration - Women's Ordination Celebration, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Bishop Cole, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 28-29)
  - Gerald Clarke, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - The Last Straw, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Documents/ letters, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Episcopal Church, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 34-35)
  - Other, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 37-46)
  - General, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  - Syracuse University chaplain, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - General, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - General, 1978-79 (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
  - General, 1978-80 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - General, 1978-81 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Women's History Conference, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - ERA information and articles, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Papers, Title IX, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - General, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 21-22)
  - General, 1979-81 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - William Schiess, 1979-88 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Chain-in, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - July service with Sonia Johnson, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - General, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 27-31)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 32-33)
  - General, 1980-81 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - ESEFI, 1980-81 (Box 7, Folder 35-39)
  - Miscellaneous feminist issues, 1980-89 (Box 7, Folder 40-41)
  - Miscellaneous feminist issues, 1980-89 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Biographical material (Seneca Falls), 1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Leters, articles, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Women's International Ministers Group, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - General, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
  - Bi-Partisan report, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Bi-Partisan Committee, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - General, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
  - Biographical material, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
  - NOW - Greater Syracuse, 1982-83 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Western Pennsylvania, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Jackie Means, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Flo Kennedy - Sonia Johnson, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - General, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
  - Westcott East Neighborhood Association, 1983-84 (Box 8, Folder 19-21)
  - Sally/Dan [Schiess/Moncheur], 1983-85 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - General, 1983-85 (Box 8, Folder 23-24)
  - Service, background, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Wedding services, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Biographical material: Staley-Mays comment, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - General, 1983-85 (Box 8, Folder 28-33)
  - "Bread" [bulletin- St. Stephen and the Incarnation, Washington, D.C.], 1984-85 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Mexico, New York, 1984-85 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - General, 1984-86 (Box 8, Folder 36-37)
  - ESEFI, 1984-86 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Job descriptions, 1984-87 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - General, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - General, 1985-86 (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
  - General, 1986-87 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Lambeth correspondence, 1986-88 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Movement for the Ordination of Women (MOW), 1986-88 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - NOW, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - NOW, IAWM, etc., 1987 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Letter to Browning after Lambeth, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 2nd decade, Houston - for report, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - General, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - General, 1987-88 (Box 9, Folder 14-15)
  - Karen De Crow, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Before Lambeth - letter from Diocese, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Lambeth - Australia, 19 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Australia - correspondence after Lambeth, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Suzanne A. Fageol, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - The British, c. 1988 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - General, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Visitor's Resolution - Lambeth, 1988-89 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Lambeth, comment re, and women during conference, 1988-89 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - At Lambeth/other countries Women's addresses, Lambeth, 1988-89 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Liz Robinson re: Lambeth New Zealand, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - ESEFI letters - May, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - IAWM, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - NOW, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - September wedding, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - General, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 31-34)
  - General, 1989-90 (Box 9, Folder 35-36)
  - General, 1989-90 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - General, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Lois and Carol Correspondence, 1994 and undated (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1992 and 1994 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Nomination of the Rev. Betty Bone Schiess to the National Women’s Hall of Fame (Karen DeCrow), not dated (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - The Faithful Eleven Conference, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Study on clergywomen in New England, not dated (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Gifts to Betty Bone Schiess from Australian women at Lambeth, 1988 (Box 11)
  - Postal cards of Oxford (Box 11)
  - Ralph E. Kharas award (1984), Master of Divinity certificate from Colgate Rochester Divinity School, (1972) (Box 11)
  - "Why Me, Lord?", 2012 (Box 11)
  - "Goodbye to All That", 2012 (Box 11)
  - RSV Bible presented to Betty Bone Schiess by Daniel Corrigan, 1974 (Box 12)
  - Engagement calendars (Box 12)
  - Printed material (Box 12)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 12)
  - Misc. Material (1990-1994) (Box 12)
  - Additional papers, including old school work (Box 14)
  - News clippings (Box 15)
  - Additional papers including correspondence, publications and women in ministry material (Box 16)
  - Additional papers including correspondence, news clippings, misc. material and ephemera (Box 17)
  - Souther Poverty Law Center certificate, 2011 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Episcopal Divinity School, 2014 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The Women's Farm, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Nomination material for National Women's Hall of Fame, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Human Rights in Syracuse: Two Memorable Decades - book, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Issue of EDS Now with article on the Philadelphia 11, 2015 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Celebrating Karen DeCrow, 2015 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Philadelphia Service - Disc A and B, 2014; CD-2368-2369 (Box 18)
  - Ordination certificates; flyer (Map-case Folder)
- Series II. Audio Cassettes
  - D. Lance (3 tapes) (Box 10)
  - Abortion (Box 10)
  - Demonstration in D.C. for ERA. Republican national Headquarters, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Lois Hayweiser Plymouth Congregational Church, Syracuse (3 tapes), Feb. 1977 (Box 10)
  - Sample sermon, Better Bone Schiess, Mollenkott speech - Women's Ministries Conference (2 tapes) Essay on Women; July 9, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Ch. 9 Special on Bi Centennial Women, Feb. 26, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Lambeth Conference - Evangelisation and Culture Bishop Jiwan, Jenkins and Gitari: women's Reflection of the Lambeth Conference (2 tapes), 1988 (Box 10)
  - Rosemary Agnotio - The "Immorality of Housewifery" (Box 10)
  - Louis Henning, Rochester NY (Box 10)
  - Betty Bone Schiess, Donna re: Prickett/Norm Smith (Box 10)
  - NOW Conference - Women and Religious Institutions (2 tapes), 1983 (Box 10)
  - Oppler NOW Salon, Jan. 20, 1987 (Box 10)
  - Interview Schiess re Acolytes Fallwell/[?], Schiess TV Interview (Box 10)
  - Sonia Johnson, Aug. 3, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Wanda Berry, May 1976 (Box 10)
  - Marian Stone NOW, Betty Bone Schiess, Jan. 1982 (Box 10)
  - Women and Men in a Changing [?] (Box 10)
  - Sidney Callahan (Box 10)
  - Theology (Box 10)
  - Supreme Court Decision: Equal Pay (Box 10)
  - News re suit filed in Federal courts and [NOW's? UNW's?] defection, July 9, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Sonia Johnson - Today Show, Jan. 1981 (Box 10)
  - Surrogate Motherhood Panel #4 (Box 10)
  - Sarah Auchincloss - Ramona Baxter Bowden (Box 10)
  - Ellen Oppler - SU Prof - NOW "Salon #2"- DeCrow (Box 10)
  - Theology Oct 22 Dr. Page Authority, Oct. 22, 1969 (Box 10)
  - Existentialism: Sartre lecture, Oct. 24, 1969 (Box 10)
  - News report - Nixon, 1974 (Box 10)
  - R. Page lecture (Box 10)
  - Theology I. Authority, Exist. I. Sartre (Box 10)
  - Harriet Harris' letters (Jonathan Corles) J.C./from Amanda and to Susan (Box 10)
  - Karen DeCrow (Box 10)
  - Betty Schiess - Karen DeCrow on Nancy Duffy's, Sept. 4, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Byline - Paul Brooks, Betty Schiess, Jan. 5, 1977 (Box 10)
  - To Betty Schiess from Mary Eunice Oliver re 1969 General Convention, Houston, 1970 (Box 10)
  - O'Connor hearings ( tapes), 1981 (Box 10)
  - Betty Bone Schiess (Box 10)
  - Letters (Box 10)
  - Dr. Carol George, Ms. Lucia Whisenand (Box 10)
  - Ed. T.V. Informed Source Betty Bone Schiess NBC News/R.C. Priests (Box 10)
- Series III. Magnetic Stripe Film
  - Ordination as Deacon, St. Paul's Syracuse, 1972 (Box 10)
- Series IV. Video Cassettes and DVD's
  - (Video is in "PAL" and is not U.S. Compatible- see Joseph Agonito collection)
  - Womanpriest: A portrait of the Rev. Betty Bone Schiess, A Day in the Life of a Newsmaker (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Womanpriest, DVD-734 (Box 10)
  - Betty Bone Schiess interview, DVD-993 (Box 10)
  - 3 Betty Bone Schiess news stories - Church of England, "Women in the Priesthood" (Box 10)
  - Anna IX-X (Box 10)
  - "Our Community" Ch 3 (NBC) Schiess, July 24, 1988 (Box 10)
  - CNY Profile - Rev. Betty Bone Schiess (Box 10)
  - Straight to the Source - Weekly Dubbing, July 29, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Lambeth Conference - Presentation of women's reflections of the Lambeth Conference, 1988 (Box 10)
  - Ooh - Schiess (Box 10)
  - Consecration of Barbara Harris (2 tapes), Feb. 11, 1989 (Box 10)
  - Newsmakers, guest: Betty Bone Schiess [VHS], 1992; V-7210 (Box 18)
  - Unidentified [VHS], n.d.; V-7211 (Box 18)
  - A Tribute to Karen DeCrow, 2015; DVD-1198 (Box 18)
    By the Central New York Women's Bar Association
  - Women Ministers, Part I and Merrill Bittnen Service, Philadelphia, 1974 (silent), n.d.; DVD-1199 (Box 18)
  - (Box 18)
- Series V. Tape Recordings
  - Betty Bone Schiess - Community House, Oct. 25, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Hayweiser and Hanmer - Human Sexuality for Hendrick's Chapel, Syracuse University (Box 10)
  - Betty Bone Schiess - Hendricks Chapel, remote at Community House, June 29, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Religion Makes News, July 11, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Lambeth (Box 10)
  - Organ Recital, Mexico, Nov. 10, 1985 (Box 10)
  - LOU 1-30, Hynn 30-49, X-mas poem (Box 10)
  - New Zealand Public Radio, 1993, TR-9325 (Box 10)
- Series VI. Film
  - Family roll - Cape Cod, 1958 (Box 10)
  - Wolf Island, 1958 (Box 10)
  - New Jersey, 1959 (Box 10)
  - Easter, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Camp, 1961 (Box 10)
  - Bermuda, 1959 (Box 10)
  - Camp, Spring (Box 10)
- Series VII. Photographs
  - Photographs - Lambeth Conference, 1988 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 11)
- Series VIII. Connie Cook Litigation Files
  - Litigation files, 1974-76 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Litigation files, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
  - Litigation files - principal cases (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Sample complaints and complaint material (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Discovery, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Exhibits (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
  - Connie Cook/ACLU and my case, 1975-76 (Box 4, Folder 12-13)
  - #1 client documents (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - ACLU (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - #1 client Wendt and Beebe trials (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Names and addresses (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - #1 client courts and judges (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Research - civil rights (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Research - conspiracy (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Ref. Women and (Religion) Episcopal Liturgy, 1972-74 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
  - #1 client - New York Human Rights (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Schiess litigation, C-1 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - #1 client - U.S. EEOC (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Convention, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Fundraising (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Validity - other priests and friends (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Complaint - correspondence (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Support Materials (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - News releases (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Newsletter - WON (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Inter-office memos (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Grace C. Kennedy (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Ordinations - blacks (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Ordination - church documents (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Ordination/custom - Catholic (Box 13, Folder 11)